Register of the Leland Barrows papers, 1942-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
Leland Barrows papers
1942-1987
97039
Hoover Institution Archives
26 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 oversize folder (11.5 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, studies, reports, memoranda, and printed matter relating to American foreign relations with South Vietnam and with Africa, especially Cameroon, Nigeria and South Africa; and to American government policy, especially as reflected in activities of the Agency for International Development, regarding foreign aid and development assistance, and promotion of foreign trade.
Barrows, Leland, 1906-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1997.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Leland J. Barrows was born in Lawrence, Kansas; he received his bachelor's and master's degrees in political science from the University of Kansas. Before World War II he worked in the Department of Agriculture, and during the war he was the Assistant Director of the War Relocation Authority.
Barrows joined the State Department in 1947 as Deputy Director of the Office of Informational and Educational Exchange and served in Paris, Rome, Athens, and Saigon as Chief of the International Cooperation Administration's mission. He also served as Regional Director for the Near East and South Asia. During the years 1960 to 1961 he served as Ambassador to Cameroon and Togo.
Upon retiring from the State Department in 1966, Barrows joined the Graduate School of Public and International Affairs at the University of Pittsburgh. He also served as a senior staff member at the Research Analysis Corporation, as the assistant to the president of the Washington Technical Institute, and as a member of the Center for Strategic and International Studies at Georgetown University.
Barrows died in Washington, D.C. on March 3, 1988.
Scope and Content Note
The Leland J. Barrows papers relate mainly to American foreign relations with South Vietnam and with Africa, especially Cameroon, Nigeria, and South Africa; and to American government policy, as reflected in the activities of the Agency for International Development, regarding foreign aid and promotion of foreign trade.
Papers that were either created by Barrows or collected by him for his projects or assignments in a professional capacity (whether as an ambassador, a senior staff member of an organization, or a member of the faculty of a university) were incorporated in the CAREER FILE. Within that large series, materials that were clearly associated with a particular position can be found under the name of the appropriate government agency, organization, or university. Those that were not are filed by the subject they cover. All other materials, either collected by Barrows for general interest or generated by others, were placed in the SUBJECT FILE.
These records bear testimony to Barrows' knowledge and expertise in the areas of U.S. foreign relations and foreign trade. Of particular interest are his reports on the Vietnam commercial import program and on race relations in South Africa.
United States. Agency for International Development.; United States. Dept. of State.; Africa--Foreign relations--United States.; Africa.; Cameroon--Foreign relations--United States.; Cameroon.; Diplomats--United States.; Economic assistance, American.; Nigeria.; South Africa.; United States--Commerce.; United States--Foreign relations--Africa.; United States--Foreign relations--Cameroon.; United States--Foreign relations--Vietnam.; United States--Foreign relations.; Vietnam--Foreign relations--United States.; Vietnam.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1942-1971 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical information and correspondence, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Background information (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Correspondence (Box-folder 1: 2-4)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-1987 (Boxes 1-2)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. See also: CAREER FILE.
  - General
    - A-B (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - C (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - D-E (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - F-H (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - I-J (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - K-N (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - P-S (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - T-W (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - African-American Institute, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - American Field Service, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - American Technical Assistance Corporation, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Angerer, Lil, 1974 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Anscheutz, Norbert, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Beanland, Gayle C., Jr., Mr. and Mrs., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Bellows, Everett H., 1966 (Box-folder 1: 21)
    Includes a letter to John Clinton re Leland Barrows. See also: Olin Mathieson Chemical Corporation.
  - Blane, John, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Blouin, Georges, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Bonsal, Philip W., 1973 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Bratton, Verl, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Buffano, Francesca, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Burns, Norman, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Carter, Chester C., 1965-1968 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - CBS News, 1967 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Center for International Communication Studies, University of Wisconsin, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Chapin, Frederic L., 1966 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Checchi and Company, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Columbia University (see also: Council on Foreign Relations, Inc.), 1971-1974 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Cottam, Howard R., 1966-1969 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (see also: Columbia University), 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Courtney, William F., 1965 (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Cresap, McCormick and Paget, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Cyr, Leo G., 1966 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Darlington, Charles, 1967 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Davis & Elkins College, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Dennis, Alfred P., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Eccleston, William E., 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Ely and Duncan, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 43)
    Includes a memorandum.
  - Enonchong, H. N. A., 1967 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - Europa Publications Limited, undated (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - Fales, Elmer C., 1965 (Box-folder 1: 46)
  - Federal Construction Corporation, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Fitzgerald, D. A., 1967 (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - Foreign Service Journal, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 50)
  - Foulon, Robert C., 1966 (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Foy, Fred C., 1973 (Box-folder 1: 52)
  - Free, Lloyd A., 1971 (Box-folder 1: 53)
    Includes an article by Lloyd A. Free.
  - Fulton, James, 1967 (Box-folder 1: 54)
  - General Cement Company (see also: A. G. Tsatsos), 1965-1969 (Box-folder 1: 55)
  - Glick, Philip M., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 56)
  - Greenberg, Hank, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 57)
  - Griffin, James Q., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 58)
  - Gulf South Research Institute, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 59)
  - Hardin, Clifford M., 1973 (Box-folder 1: 60)
  - Harry S. Truman Library Institute, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 61)
  - Heiss, John L., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 62)
  - Historical Evaluation and Research Organization, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1: 63)
  - Hofstra University, 1975 (Box-folder 1: 64)
  - Hutchinson, Edmond, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 65)
  - Indiana Central University, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1: 66)
  - Institute of African Affairs, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1: 67)
  - Institute for Defense Analysis, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 68)
  - Ise, John, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 69)
  - Johnson, Willard F., 1965 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Joseph Ruzicka, Inc., 1967 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Juge, Peter, Mr. and Mrs., 1966 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Juricak, Mary H., 1966 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Kaplan, Jacob, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Katz, Saul M., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Klein and Saks, Inc., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Kontos, C. William, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Kranzberg, Melvin, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Ladejinsky, Wolf, 1960 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Lavergne, D. C., 1966-1969 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Lawson, Eugene?, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Lukensmeyer, Richard D., 1967 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - McGreevy, G. F., 1973 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - McMenamin, Edward B., 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Marshall, John Francis, III, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Moffly, Charles K., 1965-1967 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Moffly, John W., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Moose, Richard M., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Morgan, George A., 1966 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Morris, Brewster H., 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Inc., 1966 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - New College of the University of South Florida, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - New York Times, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - Olin Mathieson Chemical Corporation, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - Olson, James C., 1967 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Palmer, Joseph, II, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Pan American World Airways, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Payton, Robert L. (see also: Hofstra University), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Penny, Freeland T., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - Phuong, Tran Huu, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - Piotrow, Frederick, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - Pitts, Malcolm E., 1967 (Box-folder 2: 35)
  - Porter International Company, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 2: 36)
    Includes a letter from William Edwards.
  - Powelson, John P., 1966-1968 (Box-folder 2: 37)
  - Presbach, Charlie, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 38)
  - Quinn, Frederick, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 39)
  - Rand Corporation, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 40)
  - Reynolds, Smith and Hills, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 41)
  - Rios, Jose E., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 42)
  - Robinson, Hamlin, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 2: 43)
  - Rockwell, Stuart, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 44)
  - Ryan, Henry A., 1965 (Box-folder 2: 45)
  - Santiago Polanco Abreu, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 46)
  - Society for the History of Technology, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 47)
  - Socony Mobil Oil Company, Inc., 1965-1966 (Box-folder 2: 48)
  - Spector, M. L., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 49)
  - Spector, Melbourne, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 50)
  - State of Arizona Development Board, 1965 (Box-folder 2: 51)
  - Stolper, Wolfgang F., 1971 (Box-folder 2: 52)
    Includes an article by Joseph A. Schumpeter.
  - Sullivan, Shea and Kenney, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 53)
  - Sullam, Victor B., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2: 54)
    Includes a letter to Arnold Kramish re Leland Barrows.
  - Superintendent of Schools, Kansas, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 55)
  - Syracuse University, 1947 (Box-folder 2: 56)
  - Tenenbaum, Edward B., 1970 (Box-folder 2: 57)
  - Thornburg, Sam C., 1972 (Box-folder 2: 58)
  - Tierney, Edward D., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 59)
  - Tsatsos, Alexander G., 1970 (Box-folder 2: 60)
  - Tyler, William R., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 61)
  - United Chapters of Phi Beta Kappa, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 62)
  - United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (see also: C. William Kontos)., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2: 63)
  - United States, Air Force, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 64)
  - United States, Congress, House of Representatives, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 65)
  - United States-Mexico Commission for Border Development and Friendship, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 66)
  - Université du Québec, 1972 (Box-folder 2: 67)
  - University of Kansas, 1966-1987 (Box-folder 2: 68)
  - University of Virginia, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 69)
  - Urban Institute, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 70)
  - Washington Post, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 71)
  - W. B. Place and Company, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 72)
  - WIIC-TV (television station, Pittsburgh, PA), 1968 (Box-folder 2: 73)
  - Westberg, undated (Box-folder 2: 74)
  - White, Thomas Raeburn, Mrs., 1968 (Box-folder 2: 75)
  - Williams, G. Mennen, Mr. and Mrs., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2: 76)
  - World Affairs Council of Pittsburgh, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 77)
  - World Health Organization, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 78)
  - Wouk, Jonathan, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 79)
  - Yost, Charles W. (see also: Council on Foreign Relations), 1969 (Box-folder 2: 80)
  - Zimmerman, Lucille L., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 81)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1946-1987 (Box 3)
  Typescript abstracts and outlines of speeches, and statements of Leland J. Barrows, arranged chronologically by title. See also: OVERSIZE FILE.
  - "An Ambassador's Report," outline for remarks, undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "The Import Component in U.S. Agricultural Exports,", undated (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - "Organizing Around an Executive: Organizing Around the Head of a Large Federal Department,", undated (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - "The Presidency and the Bureaucracy,", undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "Some Thoughts on Food and Foreign Policy,", undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - "Thoughts Stimulated by Reading Esman's 'Development Administration as a Profession,'", undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Statement, War Relocation Authority, undated (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "The Price Administrator and His Staff,", 1946 March 22 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - "Orientation of the Social Sciences Toward the Public Service," notes on panel discussion, 1947 May 15 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - "The United States and the Problems of Africa," speech, Lawrence, Kansas, and Flint, Michigan, 1965 September (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - "The Limitations of Foreign Aid," outline of speeches, Tenth Institute on Administrative Management for Development, 1966 November 9 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - "For the Purposes of United States Foreign Assistance,", 1966 December 5 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - "Advice to Newly Recruited Foreign Service Officers," remarks, Dr. Flack's class in Diplomacy and Negotiation (IA 302), U.S. Department of State?, 1967 February 2 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - "The Political Implications of International Development," outline for speeches, 1967 May 1 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - "African Economic Prospects and Problems," notes for speech, World Affairs Council, 1968 April 2 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - "The American Official Presence in Africa," speech, Lincoln University African conference, 1968 April 18-19 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    Includes brief notes.
  - "Interdisciplinary Aspects of the Application of Engineering Technology to the Industrialization of Developing countries," remarks on the influence of social and cultural environment, 1968 October 22 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - "The Future of United States Economic Aid to Underdeveloped Countries," remarks, World Affairs Seminar, Steubenville, Ohio, 1968 November 13 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - "Thoughts on the Investment Survey Program,", 1969 July 8 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Notes for seminar, 1970 February 6 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Oral history interview for the Harry S. Truman Library, Independence, Missouri, conducted in Washington, D.C., 1971 January 8 (Box-folder 3: 21)
    Includes transcript, related correspondence, and legal documents.
  - "Economic Impact of United States Military Installation Disposal Program in Vietnam,", 1971 January 13 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Oral history interview for the John F. Kennedy Library conducted in McLean, Virginia, 1971 February 4 (Box-folder 3: 23)
    Includes related correspondence.
  - Remarks, Conference on the Fifteenth Strategy for Peace, Warrenton, Virginia, 1974 October 17-24 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - "Thoughts on Non-Career Ambassadors,", 1975 August 19 (Box-folder 3: 25)
    Includes related correspondence and questionnaire.
  - Remarks, Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians, Washington, D.C., 1981 July 14 and 16 (Box-folder 3: 26)
    Includes correspondence.
  - "The American Commitment to Ngo Dinh Diem, 1954-1955," remarks, 1986 June 26 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Statement, University of Kansas, 1987 February 1 (Box-folder 3: 28)
- CAREER FILE, 1948-1987 (Boxes 3-14)
  Articles, brochures, chronological records, clippings, contracts, correspondence, interviews, itinerary, lists, memoranda, messages, newsletters, notes, outlines, programs, reports, schedule, statements, study, survey, and miscellany relating to professional activities of Leland J. Barrows, either created by Leland Barrows or collected by him in a professional capacity, arranged alphabetically by name of government agency, organization, or university. See also: SUBJECT FILE and SPEECHES AND WRITINGS.
  - General
    - General
      - Chronological file (Box-folder 3: 29)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 3: 30)
      - Financial records (Box-folder 3: 31)
      - Membership records (Box-folder 3: 32)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 3: 33)
      - Newsletters (Box-folder 3: 34)
      - Notes (Box-folder 4: 1)
      - Printed matter (Box-folder 4: 2)
      - Telegrams (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - Africa (see also: CORRESPONDENCE)
      - General
        - Financial records (Box-folder 4: 4)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 4: 5)
        - Printed matter (Box-folder 4: 6)
      - Cameroon (see also: United States, Department of State)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 4: 7)
        - Financial records (Box-folder 4: 8)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 4: 9)
        - Reports (Box-folder 4: 10)
        - Telegrams (Box-folder 4: 11)
        - Miscellany (Box-folder 4: 12)
      - Chad
        - General (Box-folder 4: 13)
        - Contracts and agreements (Box-folder 4: 14)
        - Notes (Box-folder 4: 15)
        - Reports (Box-folder 4: 16)
      - Morocco, memoranda (Box-folder 4: 17)
      - Nigeria
        - Articles (Box-folder 4: 18)
        - Briefing paper (Box-folder 4: 19)
        - Financial records (Box-folder 4: 20)
        - Lists (Box-folder 4: 21)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 4: 22)
        - Notes (Box-folder 4: 23)
        - Remarks (Box-folder 4: 24)
        - Tables (Box-folder 4: 25)
        - Telegrams (Box-folder 4: 26)
      - South Africa
        - Financial records (Box-folder 4: 27)
        - Interviews (Box-folder 4: 28)
        - Itinerary (Box-folder 4: 29)
        - Lists (Box-folder 4: 30)
        - Notes on South Africa trip, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 1)
        - Press releases (Box-folder 5: 2)
        - Reports (Box-folder 5: 3)
        - Schedule (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Agriculture
      - Clippings (Box-folder 5: 5)
      - Notes (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Asia (see also: United States Department of State)
      - General (Box-folder 5: 7-8)
      - Brochures (Box-folder 5: 9)
      - Clippings (Box-folder 5: 10)
      - Conference proceedings (Box-folder 5: 11)
      - Newsletters (Box-folder 6: 1)
      - Reports (Box-folder 6: 2-3)
    - Food supply
      - General (Box-folder 6: 4)
      - Clippings and printed matter (Box-folder 6: 5)
      - Lists (Box-folder 6: 6)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - France
      - General (Box-folder 6: 8)
      - Brochures (Box-folder 6: 9)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 6: 10)
      - Directory (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - Greece
      - Clippings (Box-folder 6: 12)
      - Lecture notes (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - International economic relations
      - General (Box-folder 6: 14)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 6: 15)
      - Notes (Box-folder 6: 16)
      - Program (Box-folder 6: 17)
      - Reports (Box-folder 6: 18)
      - Statements (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - International trade
      Includes United States Department of Commerce.
      - General (Box-folder 6: 20)
      - Chronological file (Box-folder 6: 21)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 6: 22-23)
      - Financial records (Box-folder 6: 24)
      - Lists (Box-folder 6: 25)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 6: 26)
      - Messages (Box-folder 6: 27)
      - Newsletters (Box-folder 7: 1)
      - Notes (Box-folder 7: 2)
      - Outline and task plans (Box-folder 7: 3)
      - Reports (Box-folder 7: 4)
      - Study (Box-folder 7: 5)
      - Survey (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Ocean bottom
      - General (Box-folder 7: 7)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 7: 8)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Puerto Rico, memoranda (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) (see also: Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) and SUBJECT FILE)
      - General (Box-folder 7: 11)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 7: 12)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 7: 13-14)
      - Notes (Box-folder 7: 15)
      - Program (Box-folder 7: 16)
      - Reports (Box-folder 8: 1)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - Vietnam (see also: Research Analysis Corporation)
      - General (Box-folder 8: 3)
      - Agenda (Box-folder 8: 4)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 8: 5)
      - Financial records (Box-folder 8: 6)
      - Lists (Box-folder 8: 7)
      - Memoranda (Box-folder 8: 8-9)
      - Notes (Box-folder 8: 10)
      - Outlines (Box-folder 8: 11)
      - Program (Box-folder 8: 12)
      - Remarks (Box-folder 8: 13)
      - Reports (Box-folder 8: 14-15)
      - Reports (Box-folder 9: 1)
      - Schedule (Box-folder 9: 2)
      - Study (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - Work plans (Box-folder 9: 4)
      - Miscellany (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) (see also: General/Food supply)
    - General (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Conference agenda (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Financial records (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Flyers (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - List of attendees (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - Memoranda
      - Undated (Box-folder 9: 12)
      - 1973-1975 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Monograph, "Commercial Diplomacy"
      - Typescript of individual research done by Leland Barrows under the auspices of the Center for Strategic and International Studies and used for limited circulation (Box-folder 9: 14)
      - Background material and related correspondence and memoranda (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
    - Notes (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Program (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Proposal (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Remarks (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Reports and related material (Box-folder 10: 7-9)
    - Survey (Box-folder 10: 10)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 10: 11-12)
  - National Academy of Public Administration
    - Appointment letter (Box-folder 10: 13)
    - Reports (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - National Graduate University
    - Announcements (Box-folder 10: 15)
    - Brochures (Box-folder 10: 16)
    - Bulletins (Box-folder 10: 17)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 10: 18)
    - Curriculum (Box-folder 10: 19)
    - Flyers (Box-folder 10: 20)
    - Lists (Box-folder 10: 21)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 10: 22)
    - Program (Box-folder 10: 23)
    - Prospectus (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Schedule (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Research Analysis Corporation (RAC)
    - General (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Agenda (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Agreements (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Comments (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Contract, action sheet, and notice of termination (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 11: 8-9)
    - Lists (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - Memoranda (Box-folder 11: 11-12)
    - Newsletters (Box-folder 11: 13)
    - Notes (Box-folder 11: 14)
    - Outlines (Box-folder 11: 15)
    - Proposal (Box-folder 11: 16)
    - Receipts (Box-folder 11: 17)
    - Reports (Box-folder 12: 1-4)
    - Statements (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - Work plans (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Miscellany (Box-folder 12: 7)